oracle.com 2006-06-19

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy for: www.oracle.com 

Oracle's corporate headquarters are located at:   
500 Oracle Parkway  
Redwood Shores, CA  
94065, USA  
Tel: +1.650.506.7000   
Fax: +1.650.506.7200 

Date: February 25, 2002   
Last Revised: April 17th, 2006 

Oracle Corporation and our subsidiaries and affiliates ("Oracle" or "we") respect your preferences concerning the collection and use of your personal information ("data"). Our goal is to deliver content targeted to the industry you work in, the products you use, the role you play in your organization, and your specific preferences. In order to provide you with relevant information, fulfill your specific requests, and enhance your experience across our Web site, we will at times request data from you. This policy lets you know how we collect data, why we collect it, and what choices you have concerning its use. 

This is the privacy policy for the Oracle.com Web sites. This policy describes the broadest potential use of data throughout the Oracle.com Web sites. Parts of the sites may make far less use of data than we have outlined in the policy. Please note that Oracle maintains the same privacy practices described in this policy for data we collect off-line; accordingly, references below to Web site "users" also apply to individuals from whom we collect data off-line. 

**Safe Harbor:** We are a global corporation, with operations in over 80 countries, and have developed global data practices designed to assure your personal data is appropriately protected. In light of the international nature of our business, Oracle's privacy practices are self-certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program. For more information about Safe Harbor, go to <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. While our primary data centers are in the USA, we will transfer data provided by customers to the appropriate Oracle office, distributor, partner or consultant to deliver the service or information requested by the customer. In order to provide service in a timely, cost effective and efficient manner, data provided to Oracle may be made available to authorized Oracle users across our global offices that require access to the data for business purposes. 

**Outsourcing, Support and Consulting Services.** Oracle provides a separate policy providing more detail about how we manage data we may access as part of our network-based outsourcing, support and consulting services ("Hosted Services"). Hosted Services data does not include our direct customer information, but rather the data that we may access related to our customers' customers, employees, and partners as part of our Hosted Services. A link to our Hosted Services privacy policy can be found at the end of this policy. 

**Excluded Web Sites and Magazines:** The following Oracle products and services are excluded from this policy because of their distinctive functions and practices: 

  * [Think.com](http://www.think.com/) and [Thinkquest.com](http://www.thinkquest.com/) \- Not-for-profit educational projects that help schools provide online learning environments for children. 
  * [Exchange.oracle.com](http://exchange.oracle.com/) \- An online commercial trading community, which includes hosted portals for other vendors, in which the main intent and benefit of the community is the exchange of information concerning business opportunities. 
  * [Profit Magazine and Oracle Magazine](http://www.oracle.com/oramag/misc/mag_privacy_policy.html) \- Publications available in print and from Oracle's web site. While the privacy practices for these magazines generally are consistent with this policy, mailing lists may be provided to an Oracle agent for marketing on behalf of third parties. 

Third-Party Web Sites: Oracle also provides links to non-Oracle sites we believe may be of interest to you. These sites are provided as a convenience and are beyond our control. You are advised to check the privacy policies and terms of use of those sites before providing your personal data to them. To learn more about Oracle's privacy policy, review the sections below for information pertaining to: 

  1. [TRUSTe Certification](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#truste)
  2. [ Types of Data Collection](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#data)
  3. [ Data we Collect and how we Use it](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#personal)
  4. [ Customization, Preferences, and Opt-Out](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#customization)
  5. [ Account Access](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#account)
  6. [Advertising](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#advertising)
  7. [Security](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#security)
  8. [ Compliance Issues](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#compliance)
  9. [ Policy Update](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy.html#update)

1\. TRUSTe Certification    
Oracle is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [Oracle.com](http://www.oracle.com/) and related sites. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns. 

The TRUSTe program covers only data that is collected through the Oracle Web sites covered by this policy, and does not cover data that may be collected through software downloaded from the site. 

Please note that while this privacy policy applies to Oracle.com and its related sites globally, the TRUSTe certification and Oracle's Safe Harbor Certification is limited to the US privacy practices of the Oracle.com Web sites. 

2\. Types of Data Collection   
Oracle collects data related to our users through the following methods: 

  * Automated means such as communications protocols and cookies 
  * Registration screens and online forms 
  * Sales inquiries and transactions 
  * Customer communications 
  * Offline communications and interactions 
  * Third party sources of information, such as opt in lists. 

Depending upon the method of collection and use, the data collected may include information about the user from forms, registrations and transactions (such as name, title, address, company, phone number and e-mail address), financial/transaction information (such as credit card and payment information), information about use of Oracle web sites (such as electronic communications protocols, web pages visited and cookies) and user preferences (including product requirements, areas of industry interest, newsletters, community choices and other information managed from the customer profile that is created when registering on Oracle.com). 

Electronic Communications Protocols and Cookies:  
Oracle may receive data from you as part of the communication connection itself, that is, the standard electronic greeting between your computer and our servers. This information often consists of network routing (where you came from), equipment information (browser type), date and time. At this time our server will also query your computer to see if there are "cookies" previously set by Oracle.com to facilitate log in or other site navigation procedures. A "cookie" is a small piece of information sent by a Web server to store on a Web browser so it can later be read back from that browser. 

**Cookies:** Some parts of the Oracle site use cookies to collect information about visitors' use of the Web site and to facilitate return visits. The information collected from cookies is tracked to enhance security and/or to improve the functionality of the Web site by avoiding duplicate data entry, facilitating navigation, and increasing the relevance of content. Cookies on the site may collect the following information: a unique identifier, user preferences and profile information used to personalize the content that is shown, and membership information to access Oracle's online communities. Cookies on the site, and the associated data, may be used for the purposes stated in Section 3 below. Some cookies used by Oracle.com may remain on the user's computer after they leave the Web site, but the majority is set to expire within 30 - 365 days. (As discussed in more detail below, you can set your browser to alert you to cookies being placed, in which case a prompt screen will describe information about the cookie, its duration, and the server to which it is being returned.) There may be some cookies on certain tools that are of longer duration. Cookies may also be of benefit to you by creating a more streamlined login process, keeping track of shopping cart additions and preserving order information between sessions. In the future, as we enable further customization of the site, cookies will help in assuring that information provided to you will be the most relevant to your needs. 

While we do not offer an opt-out on the site for cookies, browsers provide you with information and control over cookies. You can set your Web browser to alert you when a cookie is being used. You can also get information on the duration of the cookie and what server your data is being returned to. You then have the opportunity to accept or reject the cookie. Additionally, you can set your browser to refuse all cookies or accept only cookies returned to the originating servers. Users can generally disable the cookie feature on their browser without affecting their ability to use the site, except in some cases where cookies are used as an essential security feature necessary for transaction completion. 

**Embedded URLs:** In order to provide maximum site utility, Oracle also uses a tracking technique that uses embedded URLs to allow use of the site without cookies. Embedded URLs manifest themselves as plain text or encoded extensions to the URL that appears in the browser address or location toolbar. This technology allows limited information to follow you as you navigate the site, but is not identified to personal data and is not used beyond the session. While this increases your ability to surf the site, it does not replace the functionality or streamlining of cookies and may limit your use of many convenience features offered by the site. 

**Embedded Pixels:** In an effort to provide users with the most relevant Web site content and marketing materials, we may also use embedded pixel technologies to help track site usage and marketing campaign responsiveness. On the Web site, these technologies are used on selected pages for the purposes of identifying unique user visits as opposed to aggregate hits. The site usage information collected by these technologies is associated with cookies and may provide data about site use by registered users of www.oracle.com Web sites. This information is used to evaluate site content, navigability and composition as well as page response rates. When these technologies are used in emails, they provide information on when the email was opened. 

  * **Third Party Cookies:** Oracle has engaged Omniture, a third party, to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information (which does not include personally identifiable information) from visitors to the Web site to help us continue to improve the quality of our Web site. Omniture uses cookies to help track visitor behavior and sets cookies on behalf of Oracle that will be listed under the domain 2O7.net. Omniture does not use cookies to relate Web site visitors to any personally identifiable information. Omniture provides Oracle with information about site usage that reflects individual behavior of visitors, but not their identity. All data collected by Omniture on behalf of Oracle is used only to provide us with information on site usage and is not shared with any other third parties. Omniture information is unique to the individual, but not personally identifiable by Omniture. Omniture provides Oracle with this information which we reassociate with previously collected registration information for purposes specified in this policy, but in the main to: 
    * Select content based on registration data and movement through the site 
    * Tailor marketing to users' needs 
    * Aggregate web activity based on user registration attributes
Omniture's privacy practices have been certified by TRUSTe and can be found at [www.omniture.com](http://www.omniture.com/). 

3\. The Data We Collect and How We Use It   
Oracle collects data from users for the following purposes: 

**As a result of your site navigation.** Data may be collected to help personalize Web site content and enable navigation that is most relevant and user friendly. 

**As a result of creating an oracle.com account and filling out forms.** Data provided by you during these processes may be used to target future marketing communications that meet your needs and requirements, personalize Web site content and enable navigation that is most relevant and user friendly. 

**As a result of your joining an Oracle community, such as the Oracle Technology Network.** Information collected during this process may be used to provide relevant product alerts and updates. These updates are related to product releases, prices, terms, special offers and associated marketing campaigns. This data is sent out as part of the program member signing up for the relevant program or online account. 

**As a result of your inquiry or request for information.** Data collected as a result of your inquiry, registration for newsletters, response to marketing campaigns and other such activities may be used to respond to your inquiry, provide information requested and target future marketing communications.

**As a result of your seeking service or support.** Information collected during this process can include contact data and information related to products and service/support requested. This information may be used to provide requested services, product updates and similar notices. Oracle will pass collected information to the appropriate Oracle sales person, distributor, reseller, or consultant for follow-up related to Oracle products or services. Oracle may also ask if you wish to have your contact information shared with other selected partners that offer complementary products or services related to your inquiry. If you agree, data is provided to those partners for purpose of responding to your request for service or information. Please review the privacy policy of the specific partner regarding any further interactions with that partner.

**As a result of product download.** Product downloads rely on the contact information collected as part of the registration process. Further information may be obtained from users concerning experiences related to download and use of programs whether by trial licenses or purchase. Information may be used to confirm order information and for follow-up, marketing, and sales purposes. 

**As a result of your engagement in transactions or communications.** Information may be collected and stored as part of the transaction history. The majority of the data collected under this category is business contact information. Oracle may need to share some of this data (address, payment) with delivery services, credit card clearing houses and other similarly situated third parties that are required to accomplish the transaction.

**As a result of your participation in co-sponsored events or events hosted by partners.** We occasionally co-sponsor events with partners or present at partner events that provide services of potential benefit to Oracle users. To help assure respect of your information, we maintain control of the data we collect or limit the use of the data by these partners. 

**As a result of your participation in joint sales or joint product promotions.** Oracle and its partners may engage in joint events or provide bundled products. Such promotions will always reference the partners involved. Both Oracle and the partner(s) will have access to that information. We recommend you review the privacy policies of these partners to address your particular needs and concerns.

**As a result of referral/"tell a friend" functions.** If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. Oracle will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. Oracle uses this data for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. The friend may contact Oracle at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com) to be removed from the referral program.

**As a result of your registration for/attendance at an Oracle conference or event.** Those existing customers or registered Oracle.com users who sign up for a conference or event may be contacted prior to the event to see if any meetings, special demonstrations or other customer facilitation may be provided. This contact is in addition to any contact that may be required to confirm payment or provide logistical information and updates related to the conference. Attendees of such events may also be contacted after the event to see if any further information is required or follow up is appropriate. This information will be used only by Oracle, designated partners or conference sponsors and will not be released to other third parties. To help assure respect of your data, we maintain control of the data and require that use of the data by these partners is limited to that which is expressly relevant to your profile. Please consult the supplemental privacy statement on the specific conference site for more detailed information. 

**As a result of your participation in interactive discussions and public forums.** There are parts of the Web site that permit you to participate in interactive discussions. Some of these are moderated; all are subject to access for technical reasons. Oracle does not control the content that users post and some may serve as public discussion forums. As in any interactive forum open to many users, you should carefully consider whether you wish to submit data and should tailor any other content submitted appropriately. 

**As a result of your use of Outsourcing, Support or Consulting Services ("Hosted Services").** Some Oracle customers may provide Oracle incidental access to data about their employees, vendors, partners or customers in connection with Oracle's Hosted Services, including Oracle On Demand. As a result of this Hosted Services relationship, Oracle may access or process some of this information, but does not control the data collection or use practices related to this information. Oracle merely provides the relevant hosting or application management and support services required by the engagement. Oracle makes no independent use of the data outside of what is needed to provide the hosting service, applications management, and support or to complete specific actions requested by the customer. For a complete statement of our privacy practices related to hosted services, please review our [hosted services policy](http://www.oracle.com/html/privacy_hosted.html). 

**To address performance and fix issues.** On occasion, patches and other fixes to software, such as security patches addressing newly discovered vulnerabilities, are developed by Oracle. We may communicate the availability of these patches or fixes to registered owners of software and parties who have identified themselves to us as users or developers. 

**As a result of legal requirements.** Oracle may be required to provide data to comply with legally mandated reporting, disclosure or other legal process requirements. 

4.Customization, Preferences and Opt-Out   
Establishing an online registration profile at Oracle.com allows visitors the ability to opt in (or out) of communities and provides them with control over their preferences for electronic information delivery. 

**Communications Choices.** Oracle recognizes that users may not wish to be contacted about new or related products. Oracle.com allows you to opt out of some, or all, email marketing that may result from use of the site. These choices are established and modified via your online registration profile. A link to this profile will be available in marketing emails. You can return to the registration profile at any time to change your elections or modify your profile at <http://www.oracle.com/admin/account/index.html> or you can send an email to our general unsubscribe automated link at [unsubscribe@oracle-mail.com](mailto:unsubscribe@oracle-mail.com). If you have any problems in using any of these opt-out mechanisms, please send an email to [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com), indicate opt-out in the subject line and specify what problem you have encountered in the body of the message. 

Please note that some non-marketing communications are not subject to general opt-out. These include communications related to product download; communications about sales transactions; information about software updates, patches and fixes; disclosures to comply with legal requirements; and communications with partners about product alerts and updates. 

**Information-Sharing Choices.** Oracle only shares data with selected companies after providing users the ability to either opt out of or opt into the sharing. There are limitations to opting out in the case of (1) joint sale or joint events where the data goes to both Oracle and the other party at the same time; (2) where the customer has requested follow up which involves Oracle partners; and (3) where third parties are required to accomplish the transaction, including delivery and credit card clearing services. There may also be some cases where data is shared with third parties as a necessary function of the service, for example, posting comments to a bulletin board or posting an opportunity to an exchange, where data is available to all users. Other examples include attendance at educational or conference events where third parties and Oracle partners may be involved in providing services or sponsorship of a conference, seminar, training session, or event. As we further develop our preference tools, we will endeavor to have our partners join in their use to provide the user with a more seamless and streamlined environment. 

**Third Party Permission-Based Lists.** On occasion, Oracle may use a third party permission-based list to send communications about Oracle products and services. These are lists maintained by third parties whose users have consented to receive emails from other companies, such as Oracle. We do not have access to the names and contact information on these lists; the third party that has the direct relationship with these users maintains the list and the opt-outs, removes, and unsubscribes. We require the list owners to identify themselves as the mailers of the email and to provide appropriate opt-out mechanisms. If you wish to be removed from a third-party list, you should direct your opt-out request to the list owner, not to Oracle. Nevertheless, if you have trouble opting out, or if you wish to make us aware of any issues related to a third-party mailing, you may contact us directly at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com). When third-party mailings are sent with an Oracle reply address, Oracle also will provide a notice with information about how to opt-out of future Oracle marketing communications. 

Please contact us at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com) if you believe you have mistakenly received information after opting out or if you would like to opt out of receiving information and have been unable to use the opt-out mechanisms provided. 

5\. Access   
Oracle has provided you the ability to create an account or profile of information. We maintain the data and allow you to update it at any time. To change this information, please login as usual and follow the prompts to "update my profile." We continue to work to increase the scope of information that you may access and update. Please contact us at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com) should you require further assistance concerning your information or if you have trouble accessing your profile; please indicate access in the subject line and let us know what the access problem is in the body of the message. You may also obtain assistance by writing to us at the following address: 

1015 Fifteenth Street NW, Suite 200   
Washington DC 20005   
Attn: Chief Privacy Officer 

While the majority of questions and issues related to access can be handled quickly, complex requests may take more research and time. In such cases, access issues will either be addressed within thirty days or you will be contacted regarding the nature of the problem and appropriate next steps. 

6\. Advertising    
Oracle uses some third parties to administer a limited set of Oracle advertisements on its Web sites. No data is provided to the advertisers as part of this process, but aggregate profile information, such as user community, may be used in the selection of advertising to make sure that it has relevance to the user. On some banner ads, an embedded pixel may be present, and while it does not associate with a cookie or other personal profile information, it may return session connection information that allows advertisers to better determine how many individual users have clicked on the ad banner. 

7\. Security   
Oracle is concerned with the security of the data we have collected and has in place reasonable measures to prevent unauthorized access to that information. These measures include policies, procedures, and technical elements relating to data access controls. In addition, Oracle uses standard security protocols and mechanisms to exchange the transmission of sensitive data such as credit card details. 

In the event that individual personal data is acquired, or is reasonably believed to have been acquired, by an unauthorized person and applicable law requires notification, Oracle will notify the affected individual of the breach by email or fax or, if Oracle is unable to contact the individual by email or fax, then by U.S. mail. Notice will be given promptly, consistent with the legitimate needs of law enforcement and any measures necessary for Oracle or law enforcement to determine the scope of the breach and to assure or restore the integrity of the data system. Oracle may delay notification if Oracle or a law enforcement agency determines that the notification will impede a criminal investigation, unless and until Oracle or the agency determines that notification will not compromise the investigation. 

8\. Compliance Issues   
Oracle has appointed a Chief Privacy Officer. Should you believe your data has been used in a way that is not consistent with this policy or your stated preferences, or should you have further questions related to this policy, please contact the Chief Privacy Officer by email at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com). Written inquiries may be addressed to Chief Privacy Officer, Oracle Corporate Affairs, 1015 15th St. Ste 200, Washington DC 20005, United States of America. 

As noted in Section 4 (Customizations, Preferences, and Opt-Out) and Section 5 (Access and Registration Updates) above, Oracle provides you the ability to make choices about how we use and share data you provide to us. In addition, under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (also known as S.B. 27), if you are a California resident and your business relationship with Oracle is primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, you may request certain data regarding Oracle's disclosure, if any, of data to third parties for the third-parties' direct marketing purposes. To make a request, please send an email message to [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com) with "Request for California Privacy Information" in the subject line; you may make such a request up to once per calendar year. If applicable, we will provide you, by email, a list of the categories of data disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the third parties' names and addresses. Please note that not all data sharing is covered by S.B. 27's requirements. 

9\. Policy Updates    
If we are going to use your data in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your data in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user data already stored in our database, we will notify you by email or post a prominent notice on this Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice we will also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

We may update this policy from time to time to describe how new site features affect our use of your data and to let you know of new control and preference features that we provide you. 

We appreciate your comments on Oracle's privacy practices: [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com)
